<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: The future of academic publishing and advice for young researchers	</title>
	<atom:link href="http://fossilsandshit.com/the-future-of-academic-publishing-and-advice-for-young-researchers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/the-future-of-academic-publishing-and-advice-for-young-researchers/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-future-of-academic-publishing-and-advice-for-young-researchers</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 16:48:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Duane Nash		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/the-future-of-academic-publishing-and-advice-for-young-researchers/#comment-2785</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Duane Nash]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 16:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=1415#comment-2785</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Very good stuff Jon. I see a day, don&#039;t be dismayed it might come sooner than we realize, that yes the formal &quot;paper&quot; is deconstructed. The person who posits the hypothesis may be different than the team(s) that test it, and the person(s) who discuss those findings may be others still. While many of your thoughts on open science are correct in stipulating that inertia in academic culture and fear of a new review process are spot on the ultimate guard to a truly free and liberal open science paradigm shift is the human ego. That fear of having my idea &quot;pilfered&quot; or shared amongst many entities causes me to safeguard it; embargo it; hoard it. This becomes the crux of the dilemma; am I an ego serving science?; or is science serving my ego? When notions of &quot;first authorship&quot; and other ego-based become more nebulous and over time transparently ridiculous. When ideas are archived and shared liberally those that matter know who came up with what and it allows a tremendous acceleration of research… multiple parties testing an idea from multiple angles and methods, not beholden to embargoes or the slow speed of formal publication.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Very good stuff Jon. I see a day, don&#8217;t be dismayed it might come sooner than we realize, that yes the formal &#8220;paper&#8221; is deconstructed. The person who posits the hypothesis may be different than the team(s) that test it, and the person(s) who discuss those findings may be others still. While many of your thoughts on open science are correct in stipulating that inertia in academic culture and fear of a new review process are spot on the ultimate guard to a truly free and liberal open science paradigm shift is the human ego. That fear of having my idea &#8220;pilfered&#8221; or shared amongst many entities causes me to safeguard it; embargo it; hoard it. This becomes the crux of the dilemma; am I an ego serving science?; or is science serving my ego? When notions of &#8220;first authorship&#8221; and other ego-based become more nebulous and over time transparently ridiculous. When ideas are archived and shared liberally those that matter know who came up with what and it allows a tremendous acceleration of research… multiple parties testing an idea from multiple angles and methods, not beholden to embargoes or the slow speed of formal publication.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
