<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Should we cite preprints?	</title>
	<atom:link href="http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=should-we-cite-preprints</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 14:46:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: protohedgehog		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2828</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[protohedgehog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 14:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2325#comment-2828</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2827&quot;&gt;Steven Wooding&lt;/a&gt;.

Aha, thanks Steven! This was actually pointed out by someone on Facebook way back when, and I must have just forgotten to edit it! Thank you :)]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2827">Steven Wooding</a>.</p>
<p>Aha, thanks Steven! This was actually pointed out by someone on Facebook way back when, and I must have just forgotten to edit it! Thank you 🙂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Steven Wooding		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2827</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Steven Wooding]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 14:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2325#comment-2827</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thoughtful and useful piece - thanks.

One point (apologies if I missed it in the comments threads) - I think the question the last graph should be answering is &#039;how many pre-prints aren&#039;t published?&#039; rather than &#039;how many published articles previous appeared as preprints?&#039;]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thoughtful and useful piece &#8211; thanks.</p>
<p>One point (apologies if I missed it in the comments threads) &#8211; I think the question the last graph should be answering is &#8216;how many pre-prints aren&#8217;t published?&#8217; rather than &#8216;how many published articles previous appeared as preprints?&#8217;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Yoseph Barash		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2804</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yoseph Barash]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 17:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2325#comment-2804</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This blog + responses is a great resource for anyone thinking about this topic! Thank you all for this.

Two comments:

(1)   I have one small concrete suggestion following the recommendation in the blog (&quot;If you’re going to cite a preprint, make it clear that it’s a preprint in the reference list, and in the main text if possible&quot;):  Journals should have a visual cue for a citation which is an archived paper. This would help readers be more conscious of claims that are based on those (and therefore may warrant extra caution or looking into) compared to papers that already went through peer review. I agree that a community-based review is the future, but until this happens incorporating such a small fix would go a long way to allow citing archive papers while making readers aware they are exactly that when going through papers.

(2) (This is the ranting part) There is a related issue which has not been discussed here, about how archive papers should be treated during grant review. Sure, your own archive papers can now be cited and that&#039;s great for preliminary results (much better than writing &quot;manuscript in preparation&quot;). But what about archive papers that unsupportive grant reviewers bring as  &quot;evidence&quot; against your application?  Sure, bad peer-reviewed papers can happen just the same, but a grant reviewer would not dare to say (I think?) with the same level of authority &quot;They did not compare to X and X claims their method is bad&quot; if X was a talk they heard. In this case, though, X is an archived paper which simply states such a claim, without a shred of proof.  And X can write this in an archived paper, as there is no accountability. Sure, one could use the comment sections and start a fight every time such a claim is posted, but that can become ugly/confrontational very quickly and there is no system in place to protect you as a junior person.  I&#039;m not saying I have a clear solution, but I do think people are already abusing the archive system, whether intentionally or not.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This blog + responses is a great resource for anyone thinking about this topic! Thank you all for this.</p>
<p>Two comments:</p>
<p>(1)   I have one small concrete suggestion following the recommendation in the blog (&#8220;If you’re going to cite a preprint, make it clear that it’s a preprint in the reference list, and in the main text if possible&#8221;):  Journals should have a visual cue for a citation which is an archived paper. This would help readers be more conscious of claims that are based on those (and therefore may warrant extra caution or looking into) compared to papers that already went through peer review. I agree that a community-based review is the future, but until this happens incorporating such a small fix would go a long way to allow citing archive papers while making readers aware they are exactly that when going through papers.</p>
<p>(2) (This is the ranting part) There is a related issue which has not been discussed here, about how archive papers should be treated during grant review. Sure, your own archive papers can now be cited and that&#8217;s great for preliminary results (much better than writing &#8220;manuscript in preparation&#8221;). But what about archive papers that unsupportive grant reviewers bring as  &#8220;evidence&#8221; against your application?  Sure, bad peer-reviewed papers can happen just the same, but a grant reviewer would not dare to say (I think?) with the same level of authority &#8220;They did not compare to X and X claims their method is bad&#8221; if X was a talk they heard. In this case, though, X is an archived paper which simply states such a claim, without a shred of proof.  And X can write this in an archived paper, as there is no accountability. Sure, one could use the comment sections and start a fight every time such a claim is posted, but that can become ugly/confrontational very quickly and there is no system in place to protect you as a junior person.  I&#8217;m not saying I have a clear solution, but I do think people are already abusing the archive system, whether intentionally or not.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Turning a Critical Eye on Reference Lists - The Scholarly Kitchen		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2782</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Turning a Critical Eye on Reference Lists - The Scholarly Kitchen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 09:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2325#comment-2782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] is coming to the forefront with the popularity of preprint servers. The question being asked is whether researchers should cite preprints that have not undergone peer review. I am not going to debate that here, but the next leap is [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] is coming to the forefront with the popularity of preprint servers. The question being asked is whether researchers should cite preprints that have not undergone peer review. I am not going to debate that here, but the next leap is [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Deposit full protocols early! &#124; lushgreengrassatafridayafternoon		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2770</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Deposit full protocols early! &#124; lushgreengrassatafridayafternoon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 12:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2325#comment-2770</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] some people would not use none peer reviewed protocols that they find online (discussion here and here). I personally think it is an illusion to believe that methods get properly reviewed in papers. I [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] some people would not use none peer reviewed protocols that they find online (discussion here and here). I personally think it is an illusion to believe that methods get properly reviewed in papers. I [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Welcome to paleorXiv! - Green Tea and Velociraptors		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2759</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Welcome to paleorXiv! - Green Tea and Velociraptors]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 10:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2325#comment-2759</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] your impact. Research has shown that preprints receive more citations earlier and faster than papers not accompanied by [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] your impact. Research has shown that preprints receive more citations earlier and faster than papers not accompanied by [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Should biologists cite preprints? (yes) - Green Tea and Velociraptors		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2749</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Should biologists cite preprints? (yes) - Green Tea and Velociraptors]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 07:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2325#comment-2749</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] editorial out in The Biologist, the magazine published by The Royal Society of Biology, based on a previous discussion on this blog. It&#8217;s freely available online here, and the pretty PDF here. Here&#8217;s the full text too [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] editorial out in The Biologist, the magazine published by The Royal Society of Biology, based on a previous discussion on this blog. It&#8217;s freely available online here, and the pretty PDF here. Here&#8217;s the full text too [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Open Science has an image problem - Green Tea and Velociraptors		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2700</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Open Science has an image problem - Green Tea and Velociraptors]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 22:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2325#comment-2700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] was a response to a discussion about whether or not we should cite preprints, from around a month ago. While it is perhaps easy to understand the frustration of some when [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] was a response to a discussion about whether or not we should cite preprints, from around a month ago. While it is perhaps easy to understand the frustration of some when [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Irene Hames		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2679</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Irene Hames]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 08:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2325#comment-2679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Great to see this important post and so many taking part in the discussion. Really pleased to see the importance of citation good practice highlighted and responsibilities outlined. I’m a firm believer that citation of preprints should become a natural part of scholarly referencing and attribution, and include such citations in my own writing (preprint alone if no journal publication, both journal citation and preprint if preprint goes on to be published in a journal), e.g.

Bik, E. M., Casadevall, A., Fang, F. C. (2016) The prevalence of inappropriate image duplication in biomedical research publications. mBio, 7(3), e00809-16. doi:10.1128/mBio.00809-16. Pre-print published bioRxiv 20 April 2016. doi:10.1101/049452

Many journals won’t have considered the issue, some may not even be familiar with the concept of preprints, so I’d encourage anyone who comes across cases where preprint citation isn’t allowed to do what Marc Robinson-Rechavi has done with Nucleic Acids Research and write to the editor/managing editor. It would be very helpful to include links to good discussions on the topic to facilitate editorial board discussions. 

If citations are removed by a copyeditor, then definitely write to the editor/managing editor. Copyeditors may be working to old style manuals or a publisher’s standard guidelines and the journal editorial side may not be aware this is happening. During my 20 years as a journal managing editor I used to alert our production editors to new policies arising from our editorial board discussions and then periodically (and whenever there was a change in production editor) check they were being held to.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Great to see this important post and so many taking part in the discussion. Really pleased to see the importance of citation good practice highlighted and responsibilities outlined. I’m a firm believer that citation of preprints should become a natural part of scholarly referencing and attribution, and include such citations in my own writing (preprint alone if no journal publication, both journal citation and preprint if preprint goes on to be published in a journal), e.g.</p>
<p>Bik, E. M., Casadevall, A., Fang, F. C. (2016) The prevalence of inappropriate image duplication in biomedical research publications. mBio, 7(3), e00809-16. doi:10.1128/mBio.00809-16. Pre-print published bioRxiv 20 April 2016. doi:10.1101/049452</p>
<p>Many journals won’t have considered the issue, some may not even be familiar with the concept of preprints, so I’d encourage anyone who comes across cases where preprint citation isn’t allowed to do what Marc Robinson-Rechavi has done with Nucleic Acids Research and write to the editor/managing editor. It would be very helpful to include links to good discussions on the topic to facilitate editorial board discussions. </p>
<p>If citations are removed by a copyeditor, then definitely write to the editor/managing editor. Copyeditors may be working to old style manuals or a publisher’s standard guidelines and the journal editorial side may not be aware this is happening. During my 20 years as a journal managing editor I used to alert our production editors to new policies arising from our editorial board discussions and then periodically (and whenever there was a change in production editor) check they were being held to.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: protohedgehog		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2664</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[protohedgehog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 15:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2325#comment-2664</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2663&quot;&gt;Chris Hartgerink&lt;/a&gt;.

Hey Chris,

Yes, you&#039;re right about this part actually. So originally, I mis-interpreted the chart to show that ~100% of preprints in HEP go on to be published in journals - that would have been a stronger argument! But I edited it after noticing the mistake, and for some reason left it in rather than deleting altogether. In fact, are there any data on the proportion of preprints that eventually get published? That would actually be useful.. Looking into why things remain unpublished would also be sweet, although someone has to have worked on this before, right..?

Jon]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://fossilsandshit.com/should-we-cite-preprints/#comment-2663">Chris Hartgerink</a>.</p>
<p>Hey Chris,</p>
<p>Yes, you&#8217;re right about this part actually. So originally, I mis-interpreted the chart to show that ~100% of preprints in HEP go on to be published in journals &#8211; that would have been a stronger argument! But I edited it after noticing the mistake, and for some reason left it in rather than deleting altogether. In fact, are there any data on the proportion of preprints that eventually get published? That would actually be useful.. Looking into why things remain unpublished would also be sweet, although someone has to have worked on this before, right..?</p>
<p>Jon</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
