<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: One small step for digital Palaeontology	</title>
	<atom:link href="http://fossilsandshit.com/one-small-step-for-digital-palaeontology/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/one-small-step-for-digital-palaeontology/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=one-small-step-for-digital-palaeontology</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 20:23:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: davidpeters1954		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/one-small-step-for-digital-palaeontology/#comment-221</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[davidpeters1954]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 20:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.wordpress.com/?p=188#comment-221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jon,
I appreciate your interest in pterosaurheresies.com and I recognize your potential by the way you&#039;ve handled your own blog and the subjects therein. I&#039;m very impressed and expect great things from you as time goes by. 

Dave]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jon,<br />
I appreciate your interest in pterosaurheresies.com and I recognize your potential by the way you&#8217;ve handled your own blog and the subjects therein. I&#8217;m very impressed and expect great things from you as time goes by. </p>
<p>Dave</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Oliver Knevitt		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/one-small-step-for-digital-palaeontology/#comment-220</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Knevitt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 14:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.wordpress.com/?p=188#comment-220</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://fossilsandshit.com/one-small-step-for-digital-palaeontology/#comment-219&quot;&gt;Oliver Knevitt&lt;/a&gt;.

I meant BS - Burgess Shale btw. And here&#039;s a citation for the Gould paper, if you wanted it,

Gould, S.J. “The Disparity of the Burgess Shale Arthropod Fauna and the Limits of Cladistic Analysis: Why We Must Strive to Quantify Morphospace.” Paleobiology (1991): 411–423.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://fossilsandshit.com/one-small-step-for-digital-palaeontology/#comment-219">Oliver Knevitt</a>.</p>
<p>I meant BS &#8211; Burgess Shale btw. And here&#8217;s a citation for the Gould paper, if you wanted it,</p>
<p>Gould, S.J. “The Disparity of the Burgess Shale Arthropod Fauna and the Limits of Cladistic Analysis: Why We Must Strive to Quantify Morphospace.” Paleobiology (1991): 411–423.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Oliver Knevitt		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/one-small-step-for-digital-palaeontology/#comment-219</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oliver Knevitt]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 14:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.wordpress.com/?p=188#comment-219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Great post, as always, Jon. It all kinda reminds me of what Gould said in his 1991 paper on the BG arthropods. Forgive me for quoting pretty liberally my favourite bits,

&lt;blockquote&gt;The vague concept of evolutionary &quot;relationship&quot; includes both cladistic (branching order) and phenetic (morphological distance) components; and these are not the same, either logically or empirically. A major triumph of evolutionary studies in our generation has been, through the development of cladistics, the codification of a methodology for objective definition and determination of branching order. (The soundness of the logic does not guarantee a  resolution in every, or even in most, cases; for our world of rampant homoplasy and imperfect data often frustrates hope for confident answers.)

Success often breeds both overconfidence and overextension. Many evolutionists, intoxicated
with the victory of cladistics in its own sphere, have assumed that it must represent a panacea for all questions about &quot;relationships.&quot;  [...]

The phenetic question of defining a morphospace and mapping the distribution of actual organisms is much more difficult than the cladistic problem of determining branching order. Branching order unfolds in Newtonian time and in a space even simpler than Euclid&#039;s-the two-dimensional world of Abbott&#039;s Flatland. A morphospace, on the other hand, is not only richly multidimensional but seemingly idiosyncratic for each kind of organism. How can it be defined with anything like the rigor of cladistic space and time? In the light of this frustrating difference between rigor for branching order and verbal vagueness for morphospace, who can blame critics for their lack of sympathy with the phenetic question? Bengtson (1990: p. 115) referred to the notion of body plans as &quot;a seedy concept if there ever was any&quot;; while
Fortey (1989: p. 303) wrote: &quot;The problem with &#039;disparity&#039; is that its estimation depends on
the authority of the expert: how is he to know what makes-what is &#039;worth&#039;-a phylum? Or what a class?&quot;

We cannot assuage this frustration by importing a logically inappropriate technique like cladistics. The resolution can only arise within the structure of phenetic methods. Either we develop a set of quantitative techniques for the definition and differential filling of morphospace, or we are condemned to vagueness.

What, then, do we need? Not simply a good method for the multivariate description of organisms, for such we have (Sneath and Sokal 1973; Bookstein 1977a,b). And not even a
proper multivariate description of morphological transformation-whether by D&#039;Arcy Thompsonian (1917) coordinate transformations, Huxleyan (1932) allometric growth gradients,
or more modern methods like trend surface analysis (Sneath 1967). We need, instead, to define a full range of the abstract (and richly multivariate) space into which all organisms may fit (the morphospace). We must then be able to characterize individual organisms and plot them within this encompassing space. Finally, we need to measure density, range, clumping, and a host of other properties that determine differential filling of this totality; and we must be able to assess the variation in this differential filling through time. [...]

These questions are dauntingly difficult, and I do not pretend to have a solution. [...]

I do confess some fears that, in toto, the question of morphospace may be logically intractable,
not merely difficult. Consider the two obvious impediments: (1) All successful methods of comparison (from transformed coordinates by Albrecht Diirer to modern factor analysis) work with homologous points. How can differences be quantified if such points of comparison do not exist. Is a coral more different from an oak tree than a cow? What is the distance between a rock and a hard place? Between Scylla and Charybdis? (2)How can an objective morphospace be determined if organisms have infinite numbers of potential characters? We are not, after all, simply placing creatures into an exterior and objective Euclidian world. We are defining their morphospace in terms of their characters. Such issues may make a general solution intractable. We may not be able to answer, with satisfying rigor, the question of whether mammals evolve faster than clams: for how can teeth be compared with pallial sinuses? But science usually proceeds by resolving smaller puzzles and then moving on toward more general formulations. We should be able to establish adequate morphospaces for creatures with comparable body plans and joint possession of sufficient homologies. [...]

I have written this paper because I believe that the question of defining morphospaces and mapping their differential filling through time is so vital to our understanding of life&#039;s history, particularly to the potential contribution of paleontologists. Yet relatively little has been done in this area, despite promising starts, and despite a near assurance that smaller subdivisions of the problem are tractable (for creatures with sufficient homology), whatever the status of the full generality. I believe that a serious attack on this problem would be well worth the  concentrated attention of paleontologists with quantitative skills and evolutionary interests. Usually, when we are stymied in science, our impediment lies with missing data, thus breeding frustration; for, in such an empirical field, supply of absent data often involves an inevitable component of waiting and hoping. But, in the case of morphospace and its differential filling,
we face the much happier and resolvable issue of abundant data waiting for a technique.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

I would say that, with digital morphometrics, finally we have the technique that Gould was waiting for. A long time coming, though!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Great post, as always, Jon. It all kinda reminds me of what Gould said in his 1991 paper on the BG arthropods. Forgive me for quoting pretty liberally my favourite bits,</p>
<blockquote><p>The vague concept of evolutionary &#8220;relationship&#8221; includes both cladistic (branching order) and phenetic (morphological distance) components; and these are not the same, either logically or empirically. A major triumph of evolutionary studies in our generation has been, through the development of cladistics, the codification of a methodology for objective definition and determination of branching order. (The soundness of the logic does not guarantee a  resolution in every, or even in most, cases; for our world of rampant homoplasy and imperfect data often frustrates hope for confident answers.)</p>
<p>Success often breeds both overconfidence and overextension. Many evolutionists, intoxicated<br />
with the victory of cladistics in its own sphere, have assumed that it must represent a panacea for all questions about &#8220;relationships.&#8221;  [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The phenetic question of defining a morphospace and mapping the distribution of actual organisms is much more difficult than the cladistic problem of determining branching order. Branching order unfolds in Newtonian time and in a space even simpler than Euclid&#8217;s-the two-dimensional world of Abbott&#8217;s Flatland. A morphospace, on the other hand, is not only richly multidimensional but seemingly idiosyncratic for each kind of organism. How can it be defined with anything like the rigor of cladistic space and time? In the light of this frustrating difference between rigor for branching order and verbal vagueness for morphospace, who can blame critics for their lack of sympathy with the phenetic question? Bengtson (1990: p. 115) referred to the notion of body plans as &#8220;a seedy concept if there ever was any&#8221;; while<br />
Fortey (1989: p. 303) wrote: &#8220;The problem with &#8216;disparity&#8217; is that its estimation depends on<br />
the authority of the expert: how is he to know what makes-what is &#8216;worth&#8217;-a phylum? Or what a class?&#8221;</p>
<p>We cannot assuage this frustration by importing a logically inappropriate technique like cladistics. The resolution can only arise within the structure of phenetic methods. Either we develop a set of quantitative techniques for the definition and differential filling of morphospace, or we are condemned to vagueness.</p>
<p>What, then, do we need? Not simply a good method for the multivariate description of organisms, for such we have (Sneath and Sokal 1973; Bookstein 1977a,b). And not even a<br />
proper multivariate description of morphological transformation-whether by D&#8217;Arcy Thompsonian (1917) coordinate transformations, Huxleyan (1932) allometric growth gradients,<br />
or more modern methods like trend surface analysis (Sneath 1967). We need, instead, to define a full range of the abstract (and richly multivariate) space into which all organisms may fit (the morphospace). We must then be able to characterize individual organisms and plot them within this encompassing space. Finally, we need to measure density, range, clumping, and a host of other properties that determine differential filling of this totality; and we must be able to assess the variation in this differential filling through time. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>These questions are dauntingly difficult, and I do not pretend to have a solution. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>I do confess some fears that, in toto, the question of morphospace may be logically intractable,<br />
not merely difficult. Consider the two obvious impediments: (1) All successful methods of comparison (from transformed coordinates by Albrecht Diirer to modern factor analysis) work with homologous points. How can differences be quantified if such points of comparison do not exist. Is a coral more different from an oak tree than a cow? What is the distance between a rock and a hard place? Between Scylla and Charybdis? (2)How can an objective morphospace be determined if organisms have infinite numbers of potential characters? We are not, after all, simply placing creatures into an exterior and objective Euclidian world. We are defining their morphospace in terms of their characters. Such issues may make a general solution intractable. We may not be able to answer, with satisfying rigor, the question of whether mammals evolve faster than clams: for how can teeth be compared with pallial sinuses? But science usually proceeds by resolving smaller puzzles and then moving on toward more general formulations. We should be able to establish adequate morphospaces for creatures with comparable body plans and joint possession of sufficient homologies. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>I have written this paper because I believe that the question of defining morphospaces and mapping their differential filling through time is so vital to our understanding of life&#8217;s history, particularly to the potential contribution of paleontologists. Yet relatively little has been done in this area, despite promising starts, and despite a near assurance that smaller subdivisions of the problem are tractable (for creatures with sufficient homology), whatever the status of the full generality. I believe that a serious attack on this problem would be well worth the  concentrated attention of paleontologists with quantitative skills and evolutionary interests. Usually, when we are stymied in science, our impediment lies with missing data, thus breeding frustration; for, in such an empirical field, supply of absent data often involves an inevitable component of waiting and hoping. But, in the case of morphospace and its differential filling,<br />
we face the much happier and resolvable issue of abundant data waiting for a technique.</p></blockquote>
<p>I would say that, with digital morphometrics, finally we have the technique that Gould was waiting for. A long time coming, though!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Laurent Darras		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/one-small-step-for-digital-palaeontology/#comment-218</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Laurent Darras]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 08:33:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.wordpress.com/?p=188#comment-218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The low score of the principal component axes could well represent the fact that the measurements are independant one from another and express different aspects of the morphology, rather than a general deformative trend.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The low score of the principal component axes could well represent the fact that the measurements are independant one from another and express different aspects of the morphology, rather than a general deformative trend.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
