<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Is PLOS ONE losing favour with palaeontologists?	</title>
	<atom:link href="http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 11:05:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: protohedgehog		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2938</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[protohedgehog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 11:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2233#comment-2938</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2937&quot;&gt;Paul P.&lt;/a&gt;.

Thanks for this comment, Paul! Yes, I guess reading style and format is a tricky one. Wouldn&#039;t it be great if there was a way you could switch between them for articles? This post was written in Febrary 2017, and I am not capable of seeing the future when it comes to journal APCs.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2937">Paul P.</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks for this comment, Paul! Yes, I guess reading style and format is a tricky one. Wouldn&#8217;t it be great if there was a way you could switch between them for articles? This post was written in Febrary 2017, and I am not capable of seeing the future when it comes to journal APCs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Paul P.		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2937</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul P.]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 08:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2233#comment-2937</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Very interesting thread. I&#039;m not enamored with electronic megajournals and haven&#039;t published in one yet, mainly because they all seem to do single column pages. That might seem trivial, but it&#039;s much easier to read narrow (to a point) columns than wide columns. 

PLOS ONE, at least, used to format two columns but stopped around 2015. Why? Because it&#039;s cheaper to format the pages if they&#039;re single column. In fact, it&#039;s darn cheap because there IS no formatting! It&#039;s just a text stream of a given width, with periodic figures. The problem is, it&#039;s harder to read than narrower columns. Plus, if you print the PDF, which I do sometimes, it&#039;s even harder to read and a big waste of space due to wiiiiiide margins on each side. In fact, the wide margins give away the problem with single-column:  if the text is full-page width, it gets *really&quot; unpleasant to read.

There are other forums with people claiming that one column is better than two (well, I saw one such forum at least). Maybe those people never print a PDF, or maybe they have better monitors than I do, or maybe they never actually read a paper--maybe they just look at the pretty pictures. But the one and only reason for switching to single column instead of two columns is:  it&#039;s much easier and thus cheaper to format.

Btw, Royal Society Open Science jumped from free to $1500 per article at the start of 2018. That ain&#039;t free.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Very interesting thread. I&#8217;m not enamored with electronic megajournals and haven&#8217;t published in one yet, mainly because they all seem to do single column pages. That might seem trivial, but it&#8217;s much easier to read narrow (to a point) columns than wide columns. </p>
<p>PLOS ONE, at least, used to format two columns but stopped around 2015. Why? Because it&#8217;s cheaper to format the pages if they&#8217;re single column. In fact, it&#8217;s darn cheap because there IS no formatting! It&#8217;s just a text stream of a given width, with periodic figures. The problem is, it&#8217;s harder to read than narrower columns. Plus, if you print the PDF, which I do sometimes, it&#8217;s even harder to read and a big waste of space due to wiiiiiide margins on each side. In fact, the wide margins give away the problem with single-column:  if the text is full-page width, it gets *really&#8221; unpleasant to read.</p>
<p>There are other forums with people claiming that one column is better than two (well, I saw one such forum at least). Maybe those people never print a PDF, or maybe they have better monitors than I do, or maybe they never actually read a paper&#8211;maybe they just look at the pretty pictures. But the one and only reason for switching to single column instead of two columns is:  it&#8217;s much easier and thus cheaper to format.</p>
<p>Btw, Royal Society Open Science jumped from free to $1500 per article at the start of 2018. That ain&#8217;t free.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: protohedgehog		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2523</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[protohedgehog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 12:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2233#comment-2523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2522&quot;&gt;jay&lt;/a&gt;.

The papers with the highest retraction rates include Nature, Cell, and Science. Will you concede from publishing with them (and their associated publishers) in the future too? Retraction is so common to journals, that you&#039;d basically have to boycott all publishers rather than single any specific one out.

And that whole issue was sour. It was more like a retraction due to Twitter outrage, that was probably due to language/cultural differences and could have been resolved with a simple corrigendum, rather than any publication of &#039;legitimate&#039; Creationist research. The authors attempted to explain this in the comments of the article, and PLOS handled the entire situation was handled terribly. That being said, isn&#039;t the &#039;Arsenic Life&#039; paper published at Science still not retracted after like 10 years? ;)

I just don&#039;t see singling out any individual publishers that otherwise do/try to do a good job at publishing useful, especially in a climate when there are so many substantially worse issues with other scholarly publishers.

This comment got a bit long, sorry!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2522">jay</a>.</p>
<p>The papers with the highest retraction rates include Nature, Cell, and Science. Will you concede from publishing with them (and their associated publishers) in the future too? Retraction is so common to journals, that you&#8217;d basically have to boycott all publishers rather than single any specific one out.</p>
<p>And that whole issue was sour. It was more like a retraction due to Twitter outrage, that was probably due to language/cultural differences and could have been resolved with a simple corrigendum, rather than any publication of &#8216;legitimate&#8217; Creationist research. The authors attempted to explain this in the comments of the article, and PLOS handled the entire situation was handled terribly. That being said, isn&#8217;t the &#8216;Arsenic Life&#8217; paper published at Science still not retracted after like 10 years? 😉</p>
<p>I just don&#8217;t see singling out any individual publishers that otherwise do/try to do a good job at publishing useful, especially in a climate when there are so many substantially worse issues with other scholarly publishers.</p>
<p>This comment got a bit long, sorry!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: jay		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2522</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 12:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2233#comment-2522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While I haven&#039;t published yet with PloS, seeing that now-retracted creationist hand paper a couple of years back turned me off considering Plos.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I haven&#8217;t published yet with PloS, seeing that now-retracted creationist hand paper a couple of years back turned me off considering Plos.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Mining PLOS and PubMed data &#8211; dasaptaerwin		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2508</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mining PLOS and PubMed data &#8211; dasaptaerwin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 23:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2233#comment-2508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] post was inspired from Jon Tennant&#8217;s post on his blog (here). He was talking about the number of papers on paleontology field published in PLOSone. His post [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] post was inspired from Jon Tennant&#8217;s post on his blog (here). He was talking about the number of papers on paleontology field published in PLOSone. His post [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: And the rich get richer.. &#8211; Green Tea and Velociraptors		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2504</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[And the rich get richer.. &#8211; Green Tea and Velociraptors]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 20:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2233#comment-2504</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] the cost per article in PeerJ or PLOS ONE, and even more than the coveted Nature Communications (source), with it&#8217;s high impact/prestige [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] the cost per article in PeerJ or PLOS ONE, and even more than the coveted Nature Communications (source), with it&#8217;s high impact/prestige [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Thomas Moore		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2503</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Thomas Moore]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 03:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2233#comment-2503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#062; # You can try this with any field really

Interestingly, the general pattern and timing of decline seems to hold with almost any search term:

plot_throughtime(terms=&#039;ecology&#039;,limit=10000)
plot_throughtime(terms=&#039;sex&#039;,limit=10000)
plot_throughtime(terms=&#039;manufacturing&#039;,limit=10000)]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&gt; # You can try this with any field really</p>
<p>Interestingly, the general pattern and timing of decline seems to hold with almost any search term:</p>
<p>plot_throughtime(terms=&#8217;ecology&#8217;,limit=10000)<br />
plot_throughtime(terms=&#8217;sex&#8217;,limit=10000)<br />
plot_throughtime(terms=&#8217;manufacturing&#8217;,limit=10000)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: RichButler		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2501</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[RichButler]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 18:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2233#comment-2501</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2500&quot;&gt;protohedgehog&lt;/a&gt;.

Hi Jon, 

It&#039;s true that my statements above are based on anecdote. But I have worked as a volunteer editor for both PLOS ONE and Scientific Reports, as well as specialist journals such as JVP, Zootaxa and Pal Zeitschrift. As you know, I&#039;m particularly interested in PLOS ONE. I worked as a volunteer editor for them for two years, handling around 60 manuscripts, and was very invested in them - I believed in what they were doing, and wanted to see them succeed. I published seven of my own papers there, including some of my best anatomical work. I invested significant amounts of time and energy in PLOS ONE, but resigned in early 2014 because I was extremely disillusioned with the direction of change and the way the journal was being run. I had numerous interactions with authors as an editor, and have had many conversations about this since. 

It is true that pretty much all other journals have problems. Some of PLOS ONE&#039;s stem from the unique challenges of being a megajournal, and I saw similar problems at Scientific Reports. For example, it is very easy for a specialist journal to assign appropriate editors to manuscripts. When as a megajournal you handle vast numbers of manuscripts spanning a huge diversity of subjects it is difficult to identify appropriate editors for all of them. When I was on the editorial board PLOS ONE were not very good at this, and I frequently got asked to handle very inappropriate manuscripts (e.g. a manuscript on homicide rates and temperature in Chicago), but I saw similar issues at Scientific Reports. This is one of the reasons that I decided I was no longer going to edit for megajournals, and now only volunteer my time to JVP. 

The proofing issue is a big one for PLOS ONE. It is true that Gabi had very serious issues recently at RSOS (I was a co-author on the paper), BUT she could resolve nearly all of them by going through several rounds of proofs. As editor at PLOS ONE I saw similar issues happen during the typesetting process, but the authors had no chance to correct them, and it often took PLOS ONE months after publication to fix issues, if they were willing to do so at all. 

I agree that editorial lapses at PLOS ONE tend to get a lot of attention on social media, probably more than deserved in some cases. But the flip side is that I see open access advocates are much more willing to make excuses for PLOS ONE when such editorial mistakes happen than they are for other journals. It cuts both ways. 

I find it interesting in your data that the decline in submissions to PLOS ONE appears to begin in 2014. Coincidentally, I resigned from the editorial board in February 2014, as mentioned above, because I disagreed with the direction of travel of the journal and believed that it was damaging its reputation in the community. For interest, below are some of the points that I made at the time in my resignation letter. They are essentially the same points as I have made above:


&quot;I am resigning because of my ongoing frustration with what I perceive to be a gradual and ongoing decline in the services offered to authors and editors by PLOS ONE. I will summarise here some of the problems that have led me to decide to focus my editorial contributions elsewhere...

(1) Author proofing and manuscript production. For the &quot;no proofs&quot; model to work the production of final manuscripts needs to be highly efficient and quick to fix any problems appearing in the final manuscript. Unfortunately, I have repeatedly encountered serious problems with PLOS ONE inserting major formatting errors after manuscripts were accepted, or reproducing figures at incorrect sizes. These errors are often quite serious, make authors (justifiably) angry, and are alienating substantial segments of the palaeontological community. As both editor and as an author I have found PLOS ONE unhelpful, unwilling and slow in correcting such errors, and this further compounds the resentment felt by authors. Given the relatively high APC (higher than that of some other journals that do offer proofing), I do not understand why an author proofing service is not available.

(2) Fee waivers. There appears to be an ongoing attempt to make it ever more difficult for authors to request and obtain fee waivers, even when they clearly state that they have no access to funds. One of my PhD students recently had an unfortunate interaction with PLOS ONE with regard to this (which I have already discussed with the Editorial Office and PLOS senior management and have now resolved), but anecdotally it has been suggested to me by colleagues that he is not alone in this experience. Obviously it is important that enough fees are collected for the journal to run, but the fee waiver is critical to supporting junior researchers and researchers in institutions and countries without access to APC funds.

(3) Assignments of manuscripts to editors. I have registered my frustration elsewhere with the extremely inappropriate invitations that I have received as an editor, and the sheer volume of invitations sent out. The former is a very serious issue that is very damaging to the scientific credibility of PLOS ONE. Back in August last year, I noticed a large increase not only in the number of editorial invitations but in the number of utterly inappropriate editorial invitations... I would note that I have very specific and quite narrow keywords linked to my editorial account... I was shocked by the manuscripts that I was being asked to edit, but I also did not feel that my feedback of what to me appears to be a very major problem was treated sufficiently seriously.&quot;]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2500">protohedgehog</a>.</p>
<p>Hi Jon, </p>
<p>It&#8217;s true that my statements above are based on anecdote. But I have worked as a volunteer editor for both PLOS ONE and Scientific Reports, as well as specialist journals such as JVP, Zootaxa and Pal Zeitschrift. As you know, I&#8217;m particularly interested in PLOS ONE. I worked as a volunteer editor for them for two years, handling around 60 manuscripts, and was very invested in them &#8211; I believed in what they were doing, and wanted to see them succeed. I published seven of my own papers there, including some of my best anatomical work. I invested significant amounts of time and energy in PLOS ONE, but resigned in early 2014 because I was extremely disillusioned with the direction of change and the way the journal was being run. I had numerous interactions with authors as an editor, and have had many conversations about this since. </p>
<p>It is true that pretty much all other journals have problems. Some of PLOS ONE&#8217;s stem from the unique challenges of being a megajournal, and I saw similar problems at Scientific Reports. For example, it is very easy for a specialist journal to assign appropriate editors to manuscripts. When as a megajournal you handle vast numbers of manuscripts spanning a huge diversity of subjects it is difficult to identify appropriate editors for all of them. When I was on the editorial board PLOS ONE were not very good at this, and I frequently got asked to handle very inappropriate manuscripts (e.g. a manuscript on homicide rates and temperature in Chicago), but I saw similar issues at Scientific Reports. This is one of the reasons that I decided I was no longer going to edit for megajournals, and now only volunteer my time to JVP. </p>
<p>The proofing issue is a big one for PLOS ONE. It is true that Gabi had very serious issues recently at RSOS (I was a co-author on the paper), BUT she could resolve nearly all of them by going through several rounds of proofs. As editor at PLOS ONE I saw similar issues happen during the typesetting process, but the authors had no chance to correct them, and it often took PLOS ONE months after publication to fix issues, if they were willing to do so at all. </p>
<p>I agree that editorial lapses at PLOS ONE tend to get a lot of attention on social media, probably more than deserved in some cases. But the flip side is that I see open access advocates are much more willing to make excuses for PLOS ONE when such editorial mistakes happen than they are for other journals. It cuts both ways. </p>
<p>I find it interesting in your data that the decline in submissions to PLOS ONE appears to begin in 2014. Coincidentally, I resigned from the editorial board in February 2014, as mentioned above, because I disagreed with the direction of travel of the journal and believed that it was damaging its reputation in the community. For interest, below are some of the points that I made at the time in my resignation letter. They are essentially the same points as I have made above:</p>
<p>&#8220;I am resigning because of my ongoing frustration with what I perceive to be a gradual and ongoing decline in the services offered to authors and editors by PLOS ONE. I will summarise here some of the problems that have led me to decide to focus my editorial contributions elsewhere&#8230;</p>
<p>(1) Author proofing and manuscript production. For the &#8220;no proofs&#8221; model to work the production of final manuscripts needs to be highly efficient and quick to fix any problems appearing in the final manuscript. Unfortunately, I have repeatedly encountered serious problems with PLOS ONE inserting major formatting errors after manuscripts were accepted, or reproducing figures at incorrect sizes. These errors are often quite serious, make authors (justifiably) angry, and are alienating substantial segments of the palaeontological community. As both editor and as an author I have found PLOS ONE unhelpful, unwilling and slow in correcting such errors, and this further compounds the resentment felt by authors. Given the relatively high APC (higher than that of some other journals that do offer proofing), I do not understand why an author proofing service is not available.</p>
<p>(2) Fee waivers. There appears to be an ongoing attempt to make it ever more difficult for authors to request and obtain fee waivers, even when they clearly state that they have no access to funds. One of my PhD students recently had an unfortunate interaction with PLOS ONE with regard to this (which I have already discussed with the Editorial Office and PLOS senior management and have now resolved), but anecdotally it has been suggested to me by colleagues that he is not alone in this experience. Obviously it is important that enough fees are collected for the journal to run, but the fee waiver is critical to supporting junior researchers and researchers in institutions and countries without access to APC funds.</p>
<p>(3) Assignments of manuscripts to editors. I have registered my frustration elsewhere with the extremely inappropriate invitations that I have received as an editor, and the sheer volume of invitations sent out. The former is a very serious issue that is very damaging to the scientific credibility of PLOS ONE. Back in August last year, I noticed a large increase not only in the number of editorial invitations but in the number of utterly inappropriate editorial invitations&#8230; I would note that I have very specific and quite narrow keywords linked to my editorial account&#8230; I was shocked by the manuscripts that I was being asked to edit, but I also did not feel that my feedback of what to me appears to be a very major problem was treated sufficiently seriously.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: protohedgehog		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2500</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[protohedgehog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 13:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2233#comment-2500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2497&quot;&gt;RichButler&lt;/a&gt;.

Hey Richard,

Thanks for chipping in on this one, appreciated as always!

My main thing here was to have some numbers attached to this and measure the scope of any potential problem. Anecdote is fine, but every journal out there has issues of some sort. See Gabi&#039;s recent fiasco with RSOS, for example. Every day on Twitter I see some journal messing up somehow, like authors being invited to asked to review their own papers etc. We could discuss these issues across the board until the cows came home to little effect. The scale of this at PLOS ONE is perhaps higher, or perhaps just discussed more in public, as part of a snowballing reputation decline, as you mention. Either way, I&#039;m interested in seeing what the effect this is having on venue choice for authors. Also I&#039;m hoping that Joerg Heber, who used to be the EiC for Nature Comms but is now at PLOS ONE, will whip the journal back into shape!

Hope all is well in Brum!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2497">RichButler</a>.</p>
<p>Hey Richard,</p>
<p>Thanks for chipping in on this one, appreciated as always!</p>
<p>My main thing here was to have some numbers attached to this and measure the scope of any potential problem. Anecdote is fine, but every journal out there has issues of some sort. See Gabi&#8217;s recent fiasco with RSOS, for example. Every day on Twitter I see some journal messing up somehow, like authors being invited to asked to review their own papers etc. We could discuss these issues across the board until the cows came home to little effect. The scale of this at PLOS ONE is perhaps higher, or perhaps just discussed more in public, as part of a snowballing reputation decline, as you mention. Either way, I&#8217;m interested in seeing what the effect this is having on venue choice for authors. Also I&#8217;m hoping that Joerg Heber, who used to be the EiC for Nature Comms but is now at PLOS ONE, will whip the journal back into shape!</p>
<p>Hope all is well in Brum!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: protohedgehog		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2499</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[protohedgehog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 13:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=2233#comment-2499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2498&quot;&gt;Noam Ross&lt;/a&gt;.

That&#039;s not a bad idea. Any more advice on how to do this for a noob?]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://fossilsandshit.com/is-plos-one-losing-favour-with-palaeontologists/#comment-2498">Noam Ross</a>.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s not a bad idea. Any more advice on how to do this for a noob?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
