<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Reddit Science and the impact factor of doom	</title>
	<atom:link href="http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 19:37:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Anonymous		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/#comment-604</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anonymous]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 19:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=1668#comment-604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I can see a massive flaw in their logic just by reading their responses to your comments. They say that Mankind Quarterly, that Nazi science journal has an impact factor of 1.2, which makes it unqualified to be posted on the subreddit based on their standards. So by that logic, if the Nazi science journal somehow managed to get its impact factor up to 2.0, they would allow articles from that journal to be posted on the subreddit, whereas a legitimate scientific article that just happens to be published in a low-ranked journal (say Memoirs of Museum Victoria, or, even better, something like Australian Mammalogy, which has an impact factor of less than 1 but is heavily peer-reviewed) would be rejected.

Additionally, since the Impact Factor is seemingly defined by the average number of citations an article in that journal gets in a single year, wouldn&#039;t a journal that is published quarterly or bi-monthly as opposed to annually like the Memoirs of Museum Victoria have a lower impact factor simply because fewer articles are published annually in that journal?

In fact, I would say that /r/science&#039;s response to your queries is even worse than when it comes from high-prestige journals. When high IF-ranked journals say that your work is too specialized for publication in their journal, it is generally because they have a large number of recieved manuscripts and they are trying to choose the ones they feel will have the widest appeal to their readers per the limited space they have available. However, the way that /r/science words it, it makes it sound like they are rejecting this article &lt;i&gt;because it is not scientific enough&lt;/i&gt;.

It really does sound like they are also not accounting for the fact that impact factor scales differently for different subfields in science. I mean just looking at the impact factor for Paleontology, the top ten highest impact factor journals in Paleontology barely escape crossing over the 1.5 threshhold (according to Science Watch, http://archive.sciencewatch.com/dr/sci/10/jun6-10_2/). In fact on this list Journal of Vertebrate Paleontology, often seen as the flagship publication for Vertebrate Paleontology in general (or at least the highest ranked journal devoted solely to vert. paleo.) has an impact factor of 1.54 and would be ineligible for submission to the subreddit (admittedly this is 2008 data, data from later years are somewhat higher).

Finally, what made things really weird is that it seemed like they thought you were self-promoting your own article, as opposed to sharing the research of someone else. I would suggest the response in this case is to get a petition of a bunch of researchers saying that the article being recommended is a legitimate scientific article, but I&#039;m betting their response would be basically to say you can always round up a bunch of people to throw their support behind any issue, no matter how nonsensical.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I can see a massive flaw in their logic just by reading their responses to your comments. They say that Mankind Quarterly, that Nazi science journal has an impact factor of 1.2, which makes it unqualified to be posted on the subreddit based on their standards. So by that logic, if the Nazi science journal somehow managed to get its impact factor up to 2.0, they would allow articles from that journal to be posted on the subreddit, whereas a legitimate scientific article that just happens to be published in a low-ranked journal (say Memoirs of Museum Victoria, or, even better, something like Australian Mammalogy, which has an impact factor of less than 1 but is heavily peer-reviewed) would be rejected.</p>
<p>Additionally, since the Impact Factor is seemingly defined by the average number of citations an article in that journal gets in a single year, wouldn&#8217;t a journal that is published quarterly or bi-monthly as opposed to annually like the Memoirs of Museum Victoria have a lower impact factor simply because fewer articles are published annually in that journal?</p>
<p>In fact, I would say that /r/science&#8217;s response to your queries is even worse than when it comes from high-prestige journals. When high IF-ranked journals say that your work is too specialized for publication in their journal, it is generally because they have a large number of recieved manuscripts and they are trying to choose the ones they feel will have the widest appeal to their readers per the limited space they have available. However, the way that /r/science words it, it makes it sound like they are rejecting this article <i>because it is not scientific enough</i>.</p>
<p>It really does sound like they are also not accounting for the fact that impact factor scales differently for different subfields in science. I mean just looking at the impact factor for Paleontology, the top ten highest impact factor journals in Paleontology barely escape crossing over the 1.5 threshhold (according to Science Watch, <a href="http://archive.sciencewatch.com/dr/sci/10/jun6-10_2/" rel="nofollow ugc">http://archive.sciencewatch.com/dr/sci/10/jun6-10_2/</a>). In fact on this list Journal of Vertebrate Paleontology, often seen as the flagship publication for Vertebrate Paleontology in general (or at least the highest ranked journal devoted solely to vert. paleo.) has an impact factor of 1.54 and would be ineligible for submission to the subreddit (admittedly this is 2008 data, data from later years are somewhat higher).</p>
<p>Finally, what made things really weird is that it seemed like they thought you were self-promoting your own article, as opposed to sharing the research of someone else. I would suggest the response in this case is to get a petition of a bunch of researchers saying that the article being recommended is a legitimate scientific article, but I&#8217;m betting their response would be basically to say you can always round up a bunch of people to throw their support behind any issue, no matter how nonsensical.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Weekend reads: Manuscript submission headaches; Trophy Generation goes to grad school; is science fucked? - Retraction Watch at Retraction Watch		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/#comment-603</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Weekend reads: Manuscript submission headaches; Trophy Generation goes to grad school; is science fucked? - Retraction Watch at Retraction Watch]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 14:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=1668#comment-603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] to share a new study on Reddit? First you&#8217;ll have to make sure it comes from a journal with a high enough Impact Factor. (Jon Tennant, Green Tea and [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] to share a new study on Reddit? First you&#8217;ll have to make sure it comes from a journal with a high enough Impact Factor. (Jon Tennant, Green Tea and [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: downwithtime		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/#comment-602</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[downwithtime]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 18:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=1668#comment-602</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I agree with the sentiment that reddit, and particularly r/science offer an opportunity to broaden engagement with a wider community.  I used to post regularly there, on /r/geology and some of the other subreddits.

Reddit is often accused of being too racist, too misogynistic, too whatever, and the counter claim was always to tailor your subreddits to find your niche, but at a certain point I decided enough was enough.  The value of broadening discussion is important, but by participating in the platform you are also implicitly supporting its values &#038; the values of the community.  In the end I just couldn&#039;t anymore.  Even a board like /r/science suffers from this values creep, and it wasn&#039;t worth supporting science communication there if it meant implicitly supporting the creeps.

I&#039;ve just been waiting for an opportunity to vent :)]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I agree with the sentiment that reddit, and particularly r/science offer an opportunity to broaden engagement with a wider community.  I used to post regularly there, on /r/geology and some of the other subreddits.</p>
<p>Reddit is often accused of being too racist, too misogynistic, too whatever, and the counter claim was always to tailor your subreddits to find your niche, but at a certain point I decided enough was enough.  The value of broadening discussion is important, but by participating in the platform you are also implicitly supporting its values &amp; the values of the community.  In the end I just couldn&#8217;t anymore.  Even a board like /r/science suffers from this values creep, and it wasn&#8217;t worth supporting science communication there if it meant implicitly supporting the creeps.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve just been waiting for an opportunity to vent 🙂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: gravelinspector-Aidan		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/#comment-601</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gravelinspector-Aidan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 16:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=1668#comment-601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[... but fortunately I&#039;d got it on the clipboard.]
After reading through all this, I have still never seen a reason to go and read Reddit. Despite it&#039;s frequent referencing on Slashdot. I don&#039;t have time in my life to waste on another news aggregator.
Not that the (unpaid) mods at Reddit would probably be in the least bit bothered by this.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230; but fortunately I&#8217;d got it on the clipboard.]<br />
After reading through all this, I have still never seen a reason to go and read Reddit. Despite it&#8217;s frequent referencing on Slashdot. I don&#8217;t have time in my life to waste on another news aggregator.<br />
Not that the (unpaid) mods at Reddit would probably be in the least bit bothered by this.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: gravelinspector-Aidan		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/#comment-600</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[gravelinspector-Aidan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 16:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=1668#comment-600</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lost the damned comment between log-in and NoScript!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lost the damned comment between log-in and NoScript!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Aidan the Gravel Inspector		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/#comment-599</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aidan the Gravel Inspector]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 16:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=1668#comment-599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After reading through all this, I have still never seen a reason to go and read Reddit. Despite it&#039;s frequent referencing on Slashdot. I don&#039;t have time in my life to waste on another news aggregator.
Not that the (unpaid) mods at Reddit would (probably) be in the least bit bothered by this.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After reading through all this, I have still never seen a reason to go and read Reddit. Despite it&#8217;s frequent referencing on Slashdot. I don&#8217;t have time in my life to waste on another news aggregator.<br />
Not that the (unpaid) mods at Reddit would (probably) be in the least bit bothered by this.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Simon Dixon		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/#comment-598</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Simon Dixon]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 09:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=1668#comment-598</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I think in terms of framing this debate, it is important to say that the article was not finally rejected on the basis of IF (from your report above). There are two issues here that should be dealt with individually:
1) They use IF as their first (and primary) filter of high quality science (This is a policy issue)
2) Having done a review of this specific case they have rejected it&#039;s inclusion based on looking at the journal in question. (This is a moderator decision issue).
I think conflating the two is muddying the waters. This piece of sci-comm has NOT been denied inclusion because of IF, it has finally been denied inclusion because the journal itself is opaque about what it&#039;s peer reviewed processes are (That&#039;s not to say they are not up to standard; but the available info on it is opaque). I understand the disappointment in the decision, but procedurally it seems they gave right of appeal and looked into the case in more detail with a second opinion when requested. I&#039;m not sure *procedurally* there&#039;s a lot more they can have in place. So to use an example from my field, if I were to write something about a paper in Zeitschrift für Geomorphologie (a previously well thought of journal which has become less popular in recent decades - IF1.08) it would have been rejected on IF. if I&#039;d appealed (based on the precedent here) the mods would have been able to see the info about number of reviewers and guidelines for editors on the publisher website and based on what they have said above it may well have then been subsequently approved.

Personally I sympathise with both parties here. From the mods point of view they have two subs, an &#039;everything goes&#039; one, and a more &#039;prestigious&#039; one. Assuming we accept that there should be a filtered one (and I&#039;m guessing you do because you are fighting to be included on it!!) then it follows there has to be a filter of some kind. IF is a crude and poor way of doing it, but it is very simple and easy to implement. Effectively what it is doing in this instance is making type II errors - incorrectly rejected properly peer reviewed and interesting science. On balance that is probably better than making type I errors, and I think that is what they are arguing. This is open for debate.

I think it is unrealistic to suggest the mods at r/science should do a lot more work, (E.G. conducting detailed article level screening for every submission) so I think any potential solution which involves a lot more work isn&#039;t feasible. So if the screening policy needs to change then it would need to be replaced by something equally &#039;quick and dirty&#039; that provides a simple screen. I think constructively the best we can do to help improve the sub is to suggest alternatives. The only one I can think of is to have a list of &quot;approved&quot; journals which meet whatever standards of rigour they deem sufficient (and for transparency publish this list and the criteria behind it (likely something around clear peer review standards). This would require a lot of front end work to set up the list, but once done would likely function fairly smoothly. I&#039;m not sure that in this specific case though the journal in question (based on what the mods have said above) would have met hypothetical standards, because of their lack of info about peer review on the website.

So I&#039;m just saying I think it is more productive to focus on what their front end screening system is (and/or process more widely), rather than the individual decision.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think in terms of framing this debate, it is important to say that the article was not finally rejected on the basis of IF (from your report above). There are two issues here that should be dealt with individually:<br />
1) They use IF as their first (and primary) filter of high quality science (This is a policy issue)<br />
2) Having done a review of this specific case they have rejected it&#8217;s inclusion based on looking at the journal in question. (This is a moderator decision issue).<br />
I think conflating the two is muddying the waters. This piece of sci-comm has NOT been denied inclusion because of IF, it has finally been denied inclusion because the journal itself is opaque about what it&#8217;s peer reviewed processes are (That&#8217;s not to say they are not up to standard; but the available info on it is opaque). I understand the disappointment in the decision, but procedurally it seems they gave right of appeal and looked into the case in more detail with a second opinion when requested. I&#8217;m not sure *procedurally* there&#8217;s a lot more they can have in place. So to use an example from my field, if I were to write something about a paper in Zeitschrift für Geomorphologie (a previously well thought of journal which has become less popular in recent decades &#8211; IF1.08) it would have been rejected on IF. if I&#8217;d appealed (based on the precedent here) the mods would have been able to see the info about number of reviewers and guidelines for editors on the publisher website and based on what they have said above it may well have then been subsequently approved.</p>
<p>Personally I sympathise with both parties here. From the mods point of view they have two subs, an &#8216;everything goes&#8217; one, and a more &#8216;prestigious&#8217; one. Assuming we accept that there should be a filtered one (and I&#8217;m guessing you do because you are fighting to be included on it!!) then it follows there has to be a filter of some kind. IF is a crude and poor way of doing it, but it is very simple and easy to implement. Effectively what it is doing in this instance is making type II errors &#8211; incorrectly rejected properly peer reviewed and interesting science. On balance that is probably better than making type I errors, and I think that is what they are arguing. This is open for debate.</p>
<p>I think it is unrealistic to suggest the mods at r/science should do a lot more work, (E.G. conducting detailed article level screening for every submission) so I think any potential solution which involves a lot more work isn&#8217;t feasible. So if the screening policy needs to change then it would need to be replaced by something equally &#8216;quick and dirty&#8217; that provides a simple screen. I think constructively the best we can do to help improve the sub is to suggest alternatives. The only one I can think of is to have a list of &#8220;approved&#8221; journals which meet whatever standards of rigour they deem sufficient (and for transparency publish this list and the criteria behind it (likely something around clear peer review standards). This would require a lot of front end work to set up the list, but once done would likely function fairly smoothly. I&#8217;m not sure that in this specific case though the journal in question (based on what the mods have said above) would have met hypothetical standards, because of their lack of info about peer review on the website.</p>
<p>So I&#8217;m just saying I think it is more productive to focus on what their front end screening system is (and/or process more widely), rather than the individual decision.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: protohedgehog		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/#comment-597</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[protohedgehog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 08:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=1668#comment-597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/#comment-595&quot;&gt;Björn Brembs&lt;/a&gt;.

Yeah, I did consider sending them these. I have to respond to the latest salvo still, so will send them along and update here.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/#comment-595">Björn Brembs</a>.</p>
<p>Yeah, I did consider sending them these. I have to respond to the latest salvo still, so will send them along and update here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: brembs		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/#comment-596</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[brembs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 07:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=1668#comment-596</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sorry, I meant to say that you missed an opportunity to teach the moderators a lesson...]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sorry, I meant to say that you missed an opportunity to teach the moderators a lesson&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Björn Brembs		</title>
		<link>http://fossilsandshit.com/reddit-science-and-the-impact-factor-of-doom/#comment-595</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Björn Brembs]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 07:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fossilsandshit.com/?p=1668#comment-595</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Looks like you failed to tech the moderators there a lesson in standards of quality science: the higher the IF, the lower the quality:
http://bjoern.brembs.net/2016/01/even-without-retractions-top-journals-publish-the-least-reliable-science/
and the link to an above 1.5 journal:
http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fnhum.2013.00291/full

Why would you choose to defend your journal without much data when you can attack their journals with peer-reviewed evidence? Sounds like a strange choice of strategy to me...]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looks like you failed to tech the moderators there a lesson in standards of quality science: the higher the IF, the lower the quality:<br />
<a href="http://bjoern.brembs.net/2016/01/even-without-retractions-top-journals-publish-the-least-reliable-science/" rel="nofollow ugc">http://bjoern.brembs.net/2016/01/even-without-retractions-top-journals-publish-the-least-reliable-science/</a><br />
and the link to an above 1.5 journal:<br />
<a href="http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fnhum.2013.00291/full" rel="nofollow ugc">http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fnhum.2013.00291/full</a></p>
<p>Why would you choose to defend your journal without much data when you can attack their journals with peer-reviewed evidence? Sounds like a strange choice of strategy to me&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
